if they take you to war Yes, to fight
если вас возьмут на войну Да воевать
against your relatives who are in
против Ваших родственников которые в
Latvia
Латвии
Yeah, I’ll go, of course, and you’ll have your
Ага я пойду конечно же и будете своих
relatives in Latvia Well, if they are
родственников в Латвии Ну если они будут
armed in their hands, then
с оружием в руках то
probably
наверное
Hello Hello, where are you
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
from, the city of Kazan,
откуда город Казань
Tatarstan, and my dad served there
Татарстан да батя у меня там служил
under the Union  And where it was possible to serve
е при Союзе А где там можно было служить
there was not a
там не был
warrior
воин
of the embankment Naberezhnye Chelny and
набережной Набережные Челны и
Kazan where there is a little credit We have not
Казань где там чуть зачесть У насг не У
The thing with him is that they were these
него дело в том что они были эти
missile troops Kato mobile
ракетные войска Като передвижные
non-stationary they traveled They were not only
нестационарные они ездили Они не только
in Tatarstan but when he was there they
в Татарстане были но когда он был то они
mobile missile
Татарстану передвижные ракетные
launchers were based in Tatarstan Yes, they didn’t understand, they didn’t have a
установки Да они не вы не поняли не не
military unit, they had a military unit, well,
военная часть у них военная часть она Ну
how could they
как бы установки они
diversify the installations, he told me like
диверсифицировать мне рассказывал типа
I was born in eighty-one,
мне было я восемьдесят первого года
something I had no time to
рождения что-то мне не до того было
argue, no, no,
спорить нету то нету
no  Dad didn’t
уж батя ж не
come up with it, maybe it’s better to
придумал может быть лучше внутренние
say the internal troops are
войска сказать
not cancer, I can still believe the rocket man where
не раке я ещё могу поверить ракетчик где
we have the Strategic Missile Forces there, we don’t have the Strategic Missile Forces on
у нас там РВСН у нас нет РВСН на
the territory of
территории
Tatarstan In short, I bought it for what I
Татарстана Короче я за что купил за то
sold it for Well, okay, that was when I
продал Ну ладно хорошо это было когда я
was little, he told me I didn’t  I
был мелкий он рассказывал я не сильно
was very interested in
интересовался
the details, but now I live in Riga That is, it
детали но сейчас я в Риге живу То есть
turns out I was born I’m already in Riga
получается родился Я уже в Риге Потому
Because my father, my mother is Latvian, my father
что отец у меня мама латышка отец
Yeah, I have relatives living in Rika and
Угу У меня родственники в Рике живут и
what not, I just went to see them in
что нет я просто к ним ездил в
2010, how do you like
2010 как вам
Riga? Poor,
Рига Бедненькая
clean Well, if you
чистенько Ну если
compare  the standard of living in Latvia is better
сравнить уровень жизни в Латвии лучше
than in Russia or
чем в России или
not. It seemed the same to me,
нет Мне показалось так же также
but what the relatives are saying now is that
а вот родственники что сейчас говорят
they don’t want to move to Russia, for example,
они не хотят в Россию переехать например
well, they have a job there,
Ну у них там работа
family, children,
семья дети имущество
some property, leave everything behind and
какое-то всё бросить и
leave. Well, that is, they feel good in Latvia  Yes, as
уехать Ну то есть им хорошо в Латвии Да
I understand it, it suits them. Yes, but they
я так понимаю ну их устраивает Да а они
themselves
сами родом
were originally from Tatarstan. And Aunt Lyuda
откуда был-то из Татарстана А тётя Люда
and Uncle Zhenya were already born there,
и дядь Женя уже там родились
I understand, and two and second cousins ​​are
понял а дво а троюродные братья
already Well, too, During the Soviet Union at the
уже Ну тоже При Советском Союзе при
very end Well, the children were already born in Latvia
самом конце Ну а дети уже в Латвии
Altes
алтес язык
they study the language, yes
изучают да
And I have this second cousin. He is a
А у меня вот этот троюродный брат Он
prosecutor
прокурор
in this in some district of Riga. Well, not in
в этом в каком-то районе Риге Ну не в
Riga. But somewhere in
Риге А где-то в
the suburbs in what district. Well, somehow I do
пригороде в каком районе Ну там как-то я
n’t know how he learned from you
не знаю как у вас он
at the beginning in the police  worked
выучился в начале в милиции работал
then he trained to be a lawyer and how
потом на это выучился на юриста и как
he got there Well, in your prosecutor’s office Well, there the
его попал Ну в прокуратуру вашу Ну там
whole matter of production is in Latvian
же Всё дело производства на латышском
and Latvian yes Well, that means he somehow
идт латышском да Ну значит ему как-то
needs it And if
нужно жи А если
you don’t care what happens, Latvia,
вас не беспокоит что получается Латвия
uh, joined NATO and your relatives are in
ээ вошла в НАТО и ваши родственники в
NATO country because I have
стране НАТО потому что у меня вот есть
something like this Yes, my cousins ​​are in Rostov and
такое Да мои двоюродные они в Ростове и
we constantly have a conflict with this Yes
у нас постоянно конфликт с этим Да
because they say you have sold out there
потому что они говорят вы там продались
in short
короче
NATO if you are really straight you have
натовка если ты совсем уж прямо у тебя
such a mood Black and
такое вот настроение Чёрное и
White Well, I don’t think so  sometimes you
белые Ну я считаю так не бывает
need to eat some other
надо есть ещё какие-то другие
colors, well, here we are, if Russia
цвета хорошо вот наме если Россия
attacks Latvia, Lithuania and Estonia as if it were
нападёт на Латвию Литву и Эстонию как на
Ukraine. Well, how are you going to
Украину Да ну вы вы как будете
act? We’re attacking Latvia.
действовать мы нападаем на Латвию
Yes, I’m joining, I’m going in the front
Да я вступаю я иду в первых
row, so I’m not asking
рядах так не я спрашиваю
if they take you  war Yes, fight
если вас возьмут на войну Да воевать
against your relatives who are in
против Ваших родственников которые в
Latvia
Латвии
Yeah, I’ll go, of course, and you’ll have your
Ага я пойду конечно же и будете своих
relatives in Latvia. Well, if they’re
родственников в Латвии Ну если они будут
armed in their hands, then probably yes, but they’re
с оружием в руках то наверное да но они
on their own land and you’ll come to them on
на своей земле а вы придёте к ним на
their own land,
ихнюю землю
and that’s why And what  further What
и вот И зачем И что дальше Что для них
will change for them if we come
поменяется если мы придём
Well, as if When people come with weapons
Ну как бы Когда приходят люди с оружием
in their hands to another
в руках в другую
country Well, what will change for them
страну Ну что для них поменяется
Tell them they will live poorly Like in
Скажите будут жить бедно Как в
Russia I said
России я сказал
that I don’t know because I was I
что не я знаю пото что я был я и в
was with relatives in Rostov  This is what I saw,
Ростове был у родственников Это я видел
the dictatorship will be like in
диктатура будет как в
Russia, is there a dictatorship
России пров диктум
right, you can’t change the president,
пра вы не можете поменять президента
for example.
например
So we have irremovable power. Yes, that means you want to say that what like Vladimir Vladimirovich Putin has been in power for 20 years and does not have any support from the population, so he
поэтому он
is changing to say  that you do not have
меняется сказать что у вас нету
democratic elections in which the people
демократических выборов на которых народ
can
может
elect the head of
избирать руководителя
state, what is this
государства в чём это
manifested in the fact that candidates who
проявляется в том что кандидаты которые
can compete with the current
могут составить конкуренцию действующему
head of state are simply not allowed
главу государства просто не допускаются
to participate in
к
the elections okay
выборам хорошо Скажите
Please tell me Latvia is a parliamentary
пожалуйста Латвия парламентская
republic or a presidential
республика или президентская
parliamentary presidential
парламентско президентская
How to understand this parliamentary
Как это понять парламентская
presidential  there is a presidential there
президентская есть президентская есть
is a parliamentary there
парламентская есть парламентская
is a parliamentary presidential there is a presidential parliamentary
президентская есть президентская
presidential
парламентская президентская
parliamentary it has both the President and the
парламентская в ней есть и Президент и
parliament but the parliament has more
парламент но парламент имеет больше
powers please tell me who
полномочий скажите пожалуйста кто
is in
находится у
power in the
власти м
parliament you will take an exam I just
парламенте будете экзамен я у вас просто
want to ask you Since what year has the
хочу спросить С какого с какого года не
party group not changed yet  once a
меняется партийная группа ещё раз
party group people in elections Yes, they
партийная группа люди на выборах Да
elect whoever
выбирают кого
they want Well, and deputies How many years has
хотят Ну и депутатов Сколько сколько лет
this party group been in power
эта партийная группа находится у власти
again a party group we don’t have such a
ещё раз партийная у нас нет такого
concept of a party group in power Yes, at
понятия партийная группа у власти Да на
every election the parties receive a different
каждых выборах партии получают разное
number of votes How many how many
количество голосов Сколько сколько там
party is there Which one is in  authorities once again,
партия Какая находится у власти ещё раз
I say again, elections are held every 4-5 years
я ещё раз говорю выборы каждые 4-5 лет
with renewal, people, for example,
проходят с обновлением люди например
vote, one party gets more
голосуют получает одна партия ээ больше
then less party can be 30 years
потом меньше партия может быть и 30 лет
in parliament Yes, for example, in this in
в парламенте Да вот например в этом в ээ
America Yes, the Democratic Party and the
Америке Да демократическая партия и
Republican Party in the Senate  how many
Республиканская партия в сенате сколько
litas Yes, but that doesn’t mean that the democrats
лит Да но это не значит что демократы
came to power and that’s it, and they didn’t make
пришли к власти и всё и они не сделали
elections, they then Gop make elections, people
выборы они потом Гоп делают выборы люди
voted, the
проголосовали
president was changed, you know, and with you, you can
президент понимаешь А у вас у вас можно
change the president, you can do it in elections, as
поменять президента можно на выборах как
if he doesn’t suit the population, he
если он будет не устраивать население он
will be
будет
changed  they allowed
поменянные допустили
everyone this Who Well, I don’t know who you
всех это Кого Ну а я не знаю кого вы
want to say there were other real candidates there in general
хотите сказать там были вообще другие
Who would have won
реальные кандидаты Кто бы ему выиграл бы
against
у
him And why weren’t they allowed in No, well, I do
него А почему их не допустили Не ну вы Я
n’t know a single candidate who
вот не знаю ни одного кандидата который
could win there, so that’s not the point  how do
мог бы там победить так суть не в том
you know could or couldn’t I do
откуда вы знаете мог бы или не мог бы их
n’t allow them why Why weren’t
не допускаю че Почему не
four candidates allowed into the country in total
допускали страну четыре кандидата всего
yeah cool cool that is it
да прикольно прикольно то есть
turns out that
получается что
uh no real opposition ones for
ээ никаких реально оппозиционных вот
example was Navalny allowed to participate in the
например допустили ли Навального к
elections And he has the opportunity by law to
выборам А у него есть по закона
participate I asked if he
возможность участвовать Я спросил
was allowed  Navalny And he has
допустили Навального А у него есть
the opportunity to participate in the elections they
возможность участвовать в выборах
were allowed to allow at
допустили допустили кого-то из
least one of the oppositionists And who
оппозиционера вот хоть одного А кто там
was there I ask Well, in Russia and they
был Я спрашиваю Ну вот в России а они
were in Russia to be allowed Well,
были в России чтобы их допустили Ну как
that is, you want to say Wait, you
то есть вы хотите сказать Подождите вы
want to say that in  There are no
хотите сказать что в России Нет
oppositionists in Russia, but where are they at the
оппозиционеров ну а где они находятся на
moment? That is, there were no oppositionists in Russia,
данный момент то есть в России не было
but where are they at the
оппозиционеров да ну а где они на данный
moment? It all means you have a
момент находятся Всё значит у вас
dictatorship.
диктатура
Why Because you have no opposition. Well,
Почему Потому что у вас нет оппозиции Ну
please tell me who could
а скажите пожалуйста а кто у нас мог
be an oppositionist.  I’m asking if
быть оппозиционером я спрашиваю если у
you, if you don’t have an opposition, then
Вас если у вас нет оппозиции значит всё
you have a dictatorship
у вас диктатура
in its entirety, where did the opposition go
в полном составе куда делась оппозиция
then I, the devil knows where it
тогда Я чёрт его знает куда она
went. What happened to Ilya Yashim? What
делась Что случилось с Ильёй яшим А что
happened to him?
с ним случилось взяли посадили его и ну
-they imprisoned
его же по закону по какому-то посадили
By what law Well, I don’t know,
По какому По закону Ну я не знаю
read it according to the fake law Yes, why according to
прочитаете по фейко закону Да почему по
fake it was passed through parliament, I’m
фейко он чере парламент принят вот я же
burning dictatorship Let’s Yashin for What to
горю диктатура Давайте Яшин за Что
imprison and even Let even
посадить и даже Пускай даже
Let even if he was admitted I you
Пускай даже если бы его допустили я ты
asked you asked where where  opposition,
спросил ты спросил где где оппозиция вот
I’m asking you, here I am, this is why
я тебя спрашиваю вот я вот за что
Yashin was imprisoned, why Yasha was imprisoned. On
посадили Яшина за что посадили яши 9
December 9, he sentenced 8 years and months of general
декабря назначил 8 лет и месяцев общего
regime to the well-known oppositionist Yashin for
режима известному оппозиционера Яшина за
YouTu trans koto You say Ukraine was
YouTu транс кото Говорите Украин
imprisoned for 8 years for what he talked
садили на 8 лет за то что он рассказывал
about civilians in a storm Yes in  buche
про мирных жителей в буче Да в буче
which than no one seems to have been proven
которые чем никем вроде как не доказано
once again once again, that is, he was
ещё раз ещё раз ещё раз то есть Его
imprisoned for freedom of speech for the fact that he
посадили за свободу слова за то что он
spoke about the mine people correctly
рассказывал про минных людей правильно
Yes, on YouTube broadcasts you yourself
Да он на YouTube трансляции вы сами
read, he talked about the murder of
прочитали рассказывал про убийство
mine people in another state
минных людей в другом государстве
Yes, he is for this  he was imprisoned he argued in
Да его за это посадили он он доказывал
the affirmative reported under the guise of
утвердительно сообщил под видом
reliable information from the inhabitants of
достоверных сведений жителей
Bucha
Буча
so Russian precisely Yes, the murder of the inhabitants of
так Русский именно Да убийство жителей
Bucha This is already a proven fact and did not
бу Это уже доказанный факт причём не
provide any evidence,
привёл никаких доказательств ещё раз
look again 8 years Yes they gave the man for
смотрите 8 лет Да дали человеку за то
telling the truth
что он да рассказывал правду
about the inhabitants of Bucha by Russian soldiers
о жителей бучи российскими солдатами
reliable information  there is reliable and
достоверные сведения есть достоверные да
reliable information, all the
достоверные сведения уже все
investigations are there, there is everything, there is all
расследования есть всё есть все
reliable information, so
достоверные сведения так
the question is under what article? Yes, he was imprisoned
вопрос По какой статье Да его посадили
for 8 years discrediting the Russian army
на 8 лет дискредитации Российской армии
discrediting the Russian army That is, I
дискредитация российской армии То есть я
understand correctly that if a person of
правильно понимаю что если человек
some person yes he will receive less
какого-то человека Да он получит меньше
than
чем получил
Yashin received  no
Яшин нет
yes no There
да нет Там же есть
are also some aggravating ones there, it
там есть какие-то отягчающие есть то
turns out that there are options in which you
получается что есть варианты котором
can get less than what Yashin got.
можно получить меньше чем получил Яшин
Yes, you can get less or you can
Да может и получить меньше а может
get more, that is, man, I
получить больше то есть человек я
understand correctly that the man Yes was
правильно понимаю что человека Да за
imprisoned for 8 years for the YouTube broadcast
YouTube трансляцию посадили на 8
where he claimed that the Russian
лет где он утверждал что Российская
army, for
армия показать
example, in the United States of America, they
приме в Соединённых Штатах Америки
imprisoned a man for 8 years who
посадили на 8 лет человека который
claimed that, for example, the US army did something
утверждал что например армия США что-то
in Iraq in Vietnam, it doesn’t matter, he did something somewhere. Let’s
там в Ираке во Вьетнаме неважно где-то
remember Asan. Come on,
делал Давайте Асан же вспомним Давай
let’s Show me that
Давайте Покажите мне что на 8 лет
they imprisoned a man for 8 years.  Yes, who,
посадили человека Да который
uh, wrote something about the US Army,
ээ про армию США что-то
why do we take the United States
писал а зачем мы берём Соединённые Штаты
of America? Well, for example,
Америки Ну для примера
you love the United States of
Вы же любите Соединённые Штаты
America. Why should we take it, or for
Америки Почему мы должны брать или
example, where, show us in which country
например где вот покажите в какой стране
for what the person wrote about or on
за то что человек писал про или в
YouTube
ютубери
about the army? Yes  They imprisoned me for 8
про армию Да посадили на 8
years, I don’t know, I don’t watch.
лет я не знаю я не смотрю
Well, where in any country? Come on,
Ну где хоть на хоть в любой стране Давай
in which country was a person imprisoned for 8
в какой стране человека посадили на 8
years for a YouTube broadcast in which he
лет за YouTube трансляцию в которой он
said something about how he thinks about
что-то сказал что он вот так думает про
the army? Well, come on. There’s also
армию Ну давайте Там же
how
есть как
in England there you can be imprisoned for the
его в Англии там тебя могут посадить за
fact that the cat is specific Find the news
то что кот конкретно Найдите новость
somewhere specifically so that they eat
где-то нужно конкретно чтоб подили
Ange that Ange Well there is Asan
Анж что Анж Ну есть же Асан
who come on so And Sanju is charged well
который давай так что А санджу вменяют
and I The devil knows him Well so what do you
ну а я Чёрт его знают Ну так что ты
open T If  you don’t know why and
открываешь Т Если ты не знаешь най за
for
вед за
what And Sange has been free for a long time Well,
что А санж уже давно на свободе Ну вот
let’s say in May 2013 in North
Давайте в мае 2013 года в Северной
Carolina, twenty-year-old Donta Jamar
Каролине двадцатилетний донта джамар
Simms was sentenced to 6 months in
симмс был приговорён к 6 месяцам
prison for a series of tweets with
заключения за серию твитов с угрозами
death threats against the President of the United States with
убийства в адрес Президента США с
death threats Yes threat  murder Yes,
угрозами убийства Да угроза убийства Да
this is real Yes, the crime of threat of
это реально Да преступление угроза
murder
убийства
is in all criminal codes, there is a
есть во всех уголовных кодексах есть за
threat to unemployed people who were
угро летним безработным которые привлеки
prosecuted for a tweet with a proposal
к ответственности за твит с предложением
to get Obama with poisonous cyanide,
достать Обаму цианидом ядовитым
tried to convince the court that the guy was only
пытался убедить суд что парень только
joking, absolutely correct Yes, threat of
шутил абсолютно правильно Да угроза
murder, inciting murder - This is a
убийства подстрекать к убийства - Это
crime Yes Yashin  didn’t say to
преступление Да Яшин не говорил кого-то
kill someone Yes Yashin talked about the
убить Да Яшин рассказывал про ээ
crime of the Russian army Show me
преступление российской армии Покажи мне
yes in Britain for example in this Yes in
да в Британии например в этом Да в
America for a person to be imprisoned for 8 years
Америке чтобы человека посадили на 8 лет
Yes for stories about the army You even
Да за за рассказы про армию Ты даже
look you even saw Yes what did you read
смотри ты даже увидел Да что ты прочитал
that a person  threat of murder for 6
что человека за угрозу убийства на 6
months Yes, they imprisoned Ani for 8 years
месяцев Да там посадили Ани на 8 лет
just for broadcasting on YouTube,
просто за э трансляцию в юбе да
come on. Why, Nadi, where am I not watching
давай Чего Ну Нади где что я не смотрю
this
эти
news? We have our legislation,
новости у нас наше законодательство у
they have their own
них своё
legislation, they have case
законодательство у них прецедентное
law, we have a different law, so tell
право у нас другое право так скажи
me. Look.  you say, What did I
Смотри ты говоришь Да что я я тебе
tell you, well, find me an example so that in
сказал ну найди мне пример чтобы в
some other country, I wonder
какой-то другой стране мне интересно
what country it will be, so that a person is
какая это будет страна чтобы человека
imprisoned for 8 years for
посадили на 8 лет за то что он в юбе или
saying something about the army in YouTube or on Twitter.
в Твиттере сказал что-то про армию Да
And this is there  let it be untruthful,
свою А это там пусть будет неправдиво
they imprisoned him for 8 years, that’s
его на 8 лет посадили вот
realistic And what they should have given him I don’t
реально А что его должны были дать Я не
know Well, they were waiting for Yashina in I say where else
знаю Ну яшину ждали во я говорю где ещё
where is this in another country, at least in
где такое ещё в другой стране вот хоть в
one country there is such a practice,
одной стране есть такая практика
there is probably Well, that’s where Find You there  I
есть наверное Ну вот где Найди Ты же там
wanted something about Anzh Well, find at least
про анжа хотел что-то Ну найди хоть
something Well Anzh, let’s then,
что-то Ну Анж что давайте давайте тогда
why is Asan being
за что Асан
condemned, why is he being judged at all? Let’s
осуждают за что его вообще судят Давайте
look at Wikipedia,
в Википедии посмотрим
let’s see the material about spy scandals,
давай был материал о шпионских скандалах
corruption in the highest echelons of the authorities,
коррупции высших эшелонах властях
war crimes and the Secrets of
военных преступлениях и Тайнах
US diplomacy, specifically show what  Asan was sentenced there
США конкретно покажите что там присудили
and he was imprisoned Dawa Well, what is the
Асан ж посадили его Дава Ну за что
sentence for? Well, Yes If there is
приговор какой Ну вот Да Если есть
some kind of sentence Yes
приговор какой-то Да
Find so that we don’t discuss the news But in
Найдите чтобы мы не новости обсуждали А
reality the sentence if there is such an
реально приговор если есть тако вот
arrest in 2019
арест в 2019 году
Well, first of all, I think it’s somewhere
Ну во-первых он по-моему где-то
hid refuge in the Equa embassy in
скрывался убежище в посольстве эква в
Ecuador And so on Yes, tell me the
Эквадора И так дальше Да вот скажи
verdict
приговор
Come on, maybe it’s really there Yes,
Давай может действительно там его Да
we’ll go and see
зашёл мы посмотрим
Yes, well, he appeared in court about failure to appear in
Да ну предстал перед судом о не явки в
court so well About failure to appear su
суд так хорошо О не явки су
hundred m bydo USA San was
ста м быдо США Сан были предъявлены
charged with conspiracy with  For unlawful
обвинения в сговоре с це неправомерного
access to computer information, he is
доступа компьютерной информации
accused of trying to help
обвиняется в том что пытался помочь
Chelsea Menin generate a password for accessing
Челси менин сгенерировать паро доступа к
secret information on someone else's
секретной информации по чужой учётной
account. The punishment for such a crime
записи наказание за такое преступление
can be imprisonment for up to 5
может быть Лишение свободы на срок до 5
years, that is,
лет то есть
see illegal penetration into these er
смотри незаконное проникновение в эти ээ
access to electronic systems and so on
доступ в электронные системы и так
further, yes, that is, hacking is
дальше да то есть взлом всё это вообще
not all about freedom of speech, it’s true, it’s not
не про свободу слова правда Это не то
like And sange wrote something on Twitter and they
что А санж написал что-то в Твиттере и
started persecuting him because of it,
его начали из за этого преследовать
true No, it’s not clear That is, it was espionage,
правда Нет не за яс То есть это шпионаж
it’s
был это
espionage, where is the espionage, well, if only  if in
шпионаж где шпионаж ну е если бы если в
Russia, yes, someone will guess
России да кто-то ээ будет подбирать
some kind of passwords, yes, in order to
какие-то там пароли да Для того чтобы
hack the information of the Ministry of Defense,
взломать информацию Министерства обороны
yes, this is also espionage. And somewhere, that is, it
Да это тоже шпионаж А где то есть
turns out that Asan is not like Yashin, yes, that is,
получается Асан не как Яшин да то есть
he did not write something on Twitter or B
он не писал что-то там в Твиттере или В
Tube shouldn’t prosecute him for this. Come on, I
тубе его не за это преследовать Давай я
actually think that Yashin, no, let’s
вообще считаю что Яшин нене давай вот
find him.
найдём
I’m interested, but I’m also
вот Вот мне интересно да без мне вот
interested in the fact that a person for
интересен факт что человека за
broadcasting on
трансляцию в
YouTube created atrocity in the butch. Yes, he was
ютубером э творила бесчинство в буче Да
responsible for
ответственно за
him, they imprisoned him for 8 years, that’s really where
Его посадили на 8 лет вот реально где
this exists  still in
такое есть ещё в
the world, and probably in all countries Well,
мире да во всех наверное стран Ну вот
if in all countries at least in one Find
если во всех странах хоть в одной Найди
it, just
это ж просто ты
find it, no matter how many times you read it to me Yes,
найди ты мне сколько не зачитывал Да
everywhere somewhere or there there
всюду где-то или там угроза убийством
is some kind of death threat or espionage Yes,
получается какая-то либо шпионаж Да а
but just to write what  - that's [ __ ]
вот просто чтобы написали какую-то фигню
on Twitter Yes, and for this they were imprisoned for 8 years
в Твиттере Да и за это посадили на 8 лет
no
нет
Well, maybe they'll
Ну они другую может быть статью
come up with another article I don't know Well, let's not stop Stop,
придумают Я не знаю Ну давай не вот Стоп
let's do it like that, after all, yes, I think Yashin is a
давай так ты всё-таки да я считаю Яшин
traitor, I don't need
предатель всё мне не нужно
proof you you said you said
доказательство ты ты сказал ты сказал
that O now there is no need for proof,
что О теперь не нужно доказательства уже
yes, I read it and VH Look, you said
да я читал его и ВХ Смотри ты ты сказал
where the opposition is. Yes, I’m saying
г где оппозиционеры Да вот я же говорю
that’s where I and you started, what hurt him? I’m
вот где я и ты начал что Его задело Я же
saying, show me you have a dictatorship. You
говорю покажи мне у вас диктатура У вас
can be imprisoned for broadcasting on YouTube.  for 8
могут за трансляцию в юбе посадить на 8
years, well, maybe he still hasn’t
лет ну может он ещё что-нибудь не
done something to discredit,
выполнил дискредитировать
that is, it turns out, look, that is, you have
то есть получается смотри то есть у вас
discredited the army - this is a personal opinion
дискредитация армии - это личное мнение
The person
Человек
expresses, say
высказывает говори
Rumi, it turns out in Russia, yes If
Руми вот получается в России да Если
someone says that the Russian army
кто-то скажет что Российская армия там
committed a crime there, committed shelling,
совершила преступление совершила обстрел
for example  Kiev
например Киева
yes This Ahmadi hospital Yes, he will be imprisoned for
да Этой больниц Ахмади Да его посадят на
8 years, I understand correctly, I
8 лет я правильно понимаю я правильно
understand correctly Look, I understand correctly that
понимаю Смотри я правильно понимаю что
if now someone from Russia says
если сейчас кто-то да из России скажет
that a Russian missile flew into Ahmadi
что Российская ракета прилетела в Ахмади
[ __ ] and was
Даго
fired upon by the Russian army Tod,
с обстреляла русская армия Тода вас
most likely you have  dictatorship for what And with
всего то есть у вас диктатура по что А у
us Do you have any evidence
нас У вас есть какие-то доказательства
that it was not us who fired and you have
что это не мы обстреляли а у вас есть
some evidence that this is not so I’m
какие-то доказательства что это не так Я
generally interested Look EU no
вообще мне интерес Вот смотри ЕС нет
look come on so look no question
смотри давай давай так смотри нет вопрос
question look if you Yes  if you
вопрос смотри если вы Да если вы
imprisoned Yashin, yes, then you must
посадили Яшина да Значит у вас должны
have some evidence that he
быть какие-то доказательства что он
really was wandering there, even if there
действительно Да там брел даже если бы
was a
было по вашим этим
draconian
драконовские
investigation according to yours. Yes, it was established that he told a
следствие Да установило что он сказал
lie with the help of linguistic
неправду с помощью лингвистической
examination once again, like this, for example,
экспертизы ещё раз как это вот например
Yashin says, look, Russian army
Яшин говорит смотрите Российская армия
Yes, here are the soldiers in the video of a
Да вот тут солдаты на видео мирного
civilian, as the
жителя как
Russian investigation determined that he was
российско следствие определило что он
deceiving the SGO, I claim that the Russian
обманывает сго я утверждаю что русская
army of civilians is in trouble because uh,
армия мирных жителей в буче так как ээ
what did your justice do, how did it
что сделало ваше правосудие как оно
prove that he deceived with the help of
доказало что это он обманул с помощью
linguistic examination Well, there are norms of the
лингвистической экспертизы Ну есть нормы
Russian language, here is linguistics
русского языка вот лингвистика такая
there is such a science. What does it have to do with linguistics? If
есть Причём тут лингвистическая Если
they say that he, uh, deceived,
говорят что он ээ обманул
yes, yes, how
да да дест как
linguistically, look again at the
лингвистически ещё раз смотрите
leaflet on, for example, Yashin shows a
листика на например Яшин показывает
video of a Russian
видео как российский
soldier in a
солдатка в
booze, there are a bunch of such videos, there is a
бу есть есть куча таких видео есть есть
whole film, this documentary has been done. Look,
целый фильм прошёл этот документальный
google, and what kind of google
Посмотрите загуглите Да какой загуглите
about the storm?  what Okay Let's So
про бучу какой Хорошо Давайте Так
let's do this if I show you now I'll
давайте так если я вам сейчас покажу
show you
показываю
how to tell a soldier a ray of someone let's
как скажи солдат луче кого-то давайте
now also have a surveillance camera
сейчас тоже есть камера наблюдения
just like I'll watch this video
просто как его посмотрю это видео
Tell me where is the Russian soda let's
Скажите где русский сода давай
dial better How the clearing of the bucha took place
луше набирай Как проходила зачистка бучи
How the clearing of the buchi took place the clearing of the
Как проходила зачистка бучи зачистка
buchi Yes whole
бучи Да целое журналистское
there is a journalistic investigation somewhere in the youtube In the tube Yes, there is
расследование есть где в юбе В тубе Да
also Bucha in the form of evidence of
вот есть ещё Буча в виде доказательств
civilians of the Russian
мирных людей российской
army
армии
now only I hope this is not an agency
сечас только Надеюсь это не агентство ун
there in short, look Let me send you the name of the
там короче смотри Давай я тебе скину
videos, but
название роликов ты сечас их но
you don’t need a link I’ll send you the name
по тебе не не ссылку Я тебе название
like this  now it’s just the name
скину так сейчас просто название
Yes, there’s no need to post the link,
Да ссылку не надо
so by the way, some kind of investigator should have
так вот кстати там должны были какие-то
come there, so here’s the
это расследователь приехать так вот
first one, Bucha video, proof of the growth of the
первое вот Буча видо доказ рост
Russian army,
российскую армию
so
раз так
on. Here’s the Russian military homeland,
дальше Вот российские войсковый родына
Pete boo, Kiev region, yes, well,
Пит буу киевщина да
he’s coming, he’s coming, he’s going, he’s going,
Ну едет он едет Едет едет Едет
Here’s more  look at
Вот ещё те смотри
us here M Video nothing is
нам вот М Видео ничего не
clear to you everything is incomprehensible Well honestly it’s
понятно тебе всё непонятно Ну честно
not clear he’s
непонятно он
just tearing off all these videos it’s been a
просто поотрываю все эти видеото сри уже
long time ago
давным-давно
look I’m explaining those means Listen to me
смотри объясняю те значит Послушай меня
I showed you now you’re already
я тебе теперь показал ты уже
starting you’re already starting wait stop now
начинаешь ты уже подожди стоп теперь
listen to me You’re already starting Clear  unclear
слушай меня Ты уже начинаешь Ясно неясно
means look for everyone for a long time Everything has been clear
значит смотри уже всем давно Всё ясно
for a long time There is already an investigation
давным-давно Уже есть расследование
etc with the names Who was who and so on where
пр с фамилиями Кто кто был и так дае где
show me how much you googled look I’ll
покажите мне сколько загугли смотри я
tell you again You just yes you
тебе во ещё скажу Ты просто да ты сейчас
will now deny everything yes but it’s not visible there But it’s
будешь всё отрицать да а там не видно А
not there  then everything has been visible for a long time,
там не то уже давно всё видно давно
a huge amount of material has been collected for a long time
собраны огромнейший материалы давно
SOBR, even many have been identified Who
СОБРа идентифицированы даже многие Кто
exactly did all this Yes, in all
конкретно это всё делал Да по всем
the episodes, both you and you really You really
эпизодам и вы и Вы реально Вы реально
uh still start talking about
ээ до сих пор начинаете говорить о там
something there Bucha not Bucha fake And so on
что-то Буча не Буча фейк И так дальше Да
Yes  you simply have no conscience You are
у вас просто совести нет Вы
really a tribe tribe Yes you are in
реально племя племя Да вы вас у вас в
your cities your these soldiers are already there in
ваших городах ваши эти солдатики уже там
short and you are silent And what should you say about the butch
короче и вы молчите А что вам про бучу
because until the end of your
говорить потому что вы до конца своих
days you will say that this is a decree
дней будете говорить что это постанова
because you
потому что вы
Yes
Да имперцы
you are just imperials  - that’s all, by the way, I’ll
ты просто-напросто и всё Я кстати третье
still watch the third video of this video. I saw it and
видео ещё посмотрю это видео Я видел и
nothing is clear there at all, yes, you
там вообще ничего не понятно да да тебе
still don’t understand anything,
всё ничего не понятно
and then for some reason they approached him and
да потом они зачем-то к нему подошли ещё
did something else, and by the way, I’ll watch the third video,
что-то сделали и третью я видео кстати
let’s switch
посмотрю всё давай переключился
that’s how it was immediately incomprehensible to him, but
вот так сразу ему непонятно да стало вот
now it became such an undercut, a very important
это сейчас тако подрез очень важный
example of How Russian
пример Как работает Российская
Propaganda works Yes, they deny everything no matter what you
Пропаганда Да они всё отрицают что бы вы
give them Yes, they lie everything in
им не давали Да они всё привирает в
America also Asan Masan, let’s read How to
Америке также Асан масан давай читай Как
dip them in their own
нужно их макать в ихнее же
Guano, I’ll show you
Гуано показываю
if  you say that since with Yana
если ты говоришь что так как с яным
Show here on Twitter dadada
Покажи вот вот в Твиттере дадада
p the dude wrote that there is the President of the United States Yes
п чувак писал что там президента США Да
this is a Crime this is a threat there
это Преступление это угроза там
Zak and San and
зак а Сан а
espionage and it turns out
шпионаж и получается
that in no normal country there is such a
что ни в какой нормальной стране такого
thing Like in Russia because Russia
нету Как в России потому что Россия -
is a dictatorship  and this
это диктатура и этот
slave is Putin’s slave.
раб раб Путина
He is afraid to admit it to himself.
Он боится себе признаться в
What is the problem of many slaves,
этом в чём проблема многих рабов
they don’t understand. How can one live without
то они не понимают Как можно жить без
a slave owner? Here they have
рабовладельца вот у них есть
a bowl of food; they are there with a whip so that they don’t drive too much
миска еды их там плетью чтобы не сильно
and everything will be fine and because of
погоняли и всё будет хорошо и они из-за
their wound they are not  employer of the slave owner
своего ра не работодателя рабовладельца
Yes, they will gnaw with their teeth Because they
Да будут грызть зубами Потому что им
need this
нужна эта
bowl like squeak comment write on th
миска лайк писка комент пись на й
Telegram directly at the same time axis VN
Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube keeping
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us busy through skarg Orcs in your ban and even
нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и дуже
more videos I don’t show people at all times I don’t
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about  streams for that
показуе информация про стримы тому
in order for us to write Mali operational connection
для того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
directly infect and while there in telegra
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
okm video more tezh Tsikava and Korisna
окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we are sorry for you trimati
информация и ми повинни з вами тримати
postiyny operational connection
постийний оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Slava Ukrapis
YouTube Слава Укра пись
L
L